[music]
>> Oh, hey, hi. Welcome. Glad you guys are
here. Hey, I'm Fiddlin' Johnny and this
is my fiddle channel and magic product
review. And today we are going to be
reviewing from Murphy's Magic Studios
Sucker Punch Revolution. Man, is this a
hot release. Lots of people are chatting
about it, talking about it. Look, you
know when you come here, you're going to
get the real deal from me, my honest
opinions and thoughts,
none of the fluff.
Stick around and we'll get right into
this one.
Hello everyone.
>> [music]
>> Thank you so much for being here. I
really do appreciate it. Hey, um, you're
going to get my unfiltered thoughts on
this Murphy's Magic release of Sucker
Punch Revolution.
I do have a cold, so um, you might hear
me with a gravelly
cough every now and then. I think I
picked up something at Magic Live, so
>> [cough and clears throat]
>> bear with me. Okay, so when we talk
about this,
um, I guess I should mention that Sucker
Punch was originally released in 2016
uh, by Mark Southworth. Mark Southworth
uh, unfortunately has since passed away.
And this is the newest and updated
version with all new gaffs, nothing the
same, and with new tutorial added to it.
So it really is a uh, a new release
in essence. All right, so normally I
would talk about what are the what is
the effect or what are the effects that
are taught on here?
I don't think that's a good approach.
You're going to learn so much in the 4
and 1/2 hour tutorial here with the
gaffs that are provided in here that
you're going to have so many different
routines that you can create or create
your own unique routines that are unique
to you. So, it's not fair to do that.
But, with that said, I'm going to talk
about some of the gaps that you're able
to do or the effects that you should do.
But, you're going to be able to do the
classic Sharpie through chip.
Sound familiar? Cuz I think my last
critical review
was um
pen through coin. This is another
version of it, except you're using a
poker chip.
You're also going to be able to do
floating poker chip. Maybe I'll put that
on here or we'll put that uh demo in
here.
Poker chips turned into candy.
Vanishing and appearing chips,
transpositions, like a red chip over
here, blue chip over here, and suddenly
close your hands and they've changed
positions. Uh Scotch and Soda routines,
multiple Scotch and Soda routines. And
really many, many more so that you can
jam and create your own routines. Let's
talk about
This is the box. What are you going to
get in the box? So, there's a bunch of
gimmicks in here. There's technically 10
poker chips. Uh some are get gimmick and
others are not. Um but, the specific
gimmicks, kind of repeating myself a
little bit here, is Sharpie through uh
chip, a floating chip, a flipper chip,
an expanded shell chip, a slippery Sam
chip, uh the chip to be able to do chip
in bottle,
an exploding chip, and regular poker
chips. Now,
>> [clears throat]
>> if you are not familiar with some of
those language that I used, this might
be a great
uh sort of release for you. In that, it
will explain expand your repertoire and
knowledge of different coin gaps that
have been built in essentially to a
poker chip.
All right, you're also going to get like
Let me just kind of show you like Here's
the box that it comes in. You're also
going to get this
uh
a bunch of stickers that can be added,
let's say,
>> [clears throat]
>> to customize some of the chips. Most of
the chips all come in red, but if you
want to make some blue chips, boom, you
got enough stickers to do that. With
replacement stickers should they wear
out, you're going to get some elastic as
well if you need to repair your flipper
chip
as well. So, those are some of the
things that are in there
uh in in the box. So,
let's talk about what else do you get?
You're going to get four
independent tutorials plus an additional
one live performances tutorial, and
they're all sort of separated. Each are
over an hour in length.
There's a total of 4 and 1/2 hours of
tutorial on this, which is
mind-blowing. But, in addition to that,
you're going to get live performances in
the wild performed by adults to adults,
which really gives you the proof in the
pudding that whatever you think about
this, these work and they do the job as
advertised.
All right, let's talk about one of the
things that are most important. How are
the instructions? You get 4 and 1/2
hours of instruction. They're on the
Murphy's Magic site, which means you can
download these.
They are taught by
professional coin magician Craig Petty.
Maybe you've heard of him.
But, Craig Petty
really gives you a masterclass in coin
slides and routines. And I'm going to
use the word coin and I'll use chips
interdependent because really for me
this is a the training wheels and
starter pack to become really a great
coin magician at an affordable price. Um
basically, he's going to teach you so
many different routines on here. I lost
count of all the different types of
routines that he taught on here.
Um so, you really can pick what fits,
what suits you, and tailors for you.
But, in addition to that, there are
details on the slides, which I think is
probably where the gold is in this one.
Because once you learn all the slides,
you see all the different routines, the
truth is you can go out and start
jamming and creating your own routines.
It allows you to be creative on your own
that maybe you like elements of some of
these routines, but if you want to
change them yourself, once you know
those
slides and you understand how the
gimmicks work, you can begin to create
routines that really suit you.
And I think that's a nice aspect of this
release.
So, the instructions, quite honestly,
are fantastic. I would say
chef's kiss on this one. One of the
better tutorials that I have seen in
quite a quite a quite a while.
Eventually, my tongue and lips will work
together.
Um
we should talk about how are the
gimmicks, cuz this is where I think
people will be critical and some of that
criticism I may
agree with,
but some of it may be misguided in my
humble opinion.
>> [clears throat]
>> So, let's start with the criticism
first. Not my criticism, but I believe
this will be criticism that people will
have. They will say that these chips
well, they kind of look like they're not
real poker chips. They're plastic. They
look they don't they're not made of clay
in the way a real casino poker chip is.
So, like how are people going to believe
they're poker chips?
Uh that's fair enough. Uh you're right,
they don't feel like a real
uh casino poker chip. They don't feel uh
they don't honestly
completely look like something that came
from a real casino. Some people might
even or like something you know, if you
if the boys and the gals are playing
poker uh on a weekend and you got a nice
chip set, you know, they'll go these are
cheap cheap chips. And they would not be
wrong. Some people might even say and go
as far as like they look like toy chips.
And to some, yeah, they probably do look
like toy chips. And I'll be honest, that
is a criticism that would not be
inaccurate. I would counter it, however,
because the tutorial is so good and the
gaps work exactly as advertised
that once you start performing the
routines,
people will forget that these do not
look like real casino poker chips and be
amazed and wowed by the actual effects
that you are producing. So, for the
negative nellies out there who say,
"These look like kids toy chips." Sure,
but the important point is your
performance and the effect that you're
creating. And the second you create a
great, strong, powerful effect, which
you can do with all of these,
they'll forget what they look like and
just be in awe. That's my takeaway and
for the negative nellies out there,
take that in your poker chip and think
about it.
Okay, maybe that's not the right
analogy. All right, so
>> [clears throat]
>> what else would I say about the poker
chips?
The gaps work. They do what they're
supposed to. Um if, let's say, they wear
out like the stickers over time, you get
the sticker pack. Just tack on some new
stickers. You get a bunch of them. I
understand Murphy's Magic will be
selling sticker packs as well in the
future. So, should they wear out, just
get new stickers and slap them right on
there and you're good and you're off to
the races again or maybe the casino. Um
so,
um
they'll last. They're plastic. They'll
should last forever. Only thing that
will wear out is the sticker. Buy new
stickers on them if you need to uh
moving forward.
All right.
We should move into what is the skill
level. This is really important here.
I think I was amazed by how
simple
most of the slides were to produce
really strong effects on this. And maybe
I'm a little jaded because I've been
doing magic since I was like 5 years
old, right?
Um but um
I found all of the slides
nothing intimidating is what I think I
really want to point out. Nothing's
intimidating here.
Um but the effects are really really
strong and they are professional level
strong. Meaning that every professional
you've ever seen doing coin magic has
done and used these gaps, have done and
used these slides. And in particular,
especially so when we're talking about
skill level, I believe
who this is best for is somebody who
really wants to do coin magic
and wants to do coin magic with gaff
coin gaffed coins, this is a great
starter pack and you should strongly
consider.
It's really good, quite honestly. Um if
you've dabbled a little bit and you want
to expand, worth considering. If you
have the original sucker punch and you
want to learn new routines with
different uh gaffs, worth considering.
But in particular, if you're a coin
magician you've been doing coin
magic for a long time, this is not for
you. If you dabble a little bit, it may
be for you. Uh but if you really are a
beginner and want to learn good coin
magic with poker chips that will
translate to gaffed coins, this is the
great way to go. Especially at the price
point, which I'll talk about here
shortly. Most of this would be worth of
$500 if you were buying this with coins
and this is nowhere near that. In fact,
it might be close to 500 up to $1,000 if
you were to buy these as coins. So, it's
a great way to see do you like them,
are you able to perform with them easy,
and if you wanted to then you start uh
buying maybe more expensive coins
eventually. But it's the gateway
to really good coin magic with coin
gaffs.
But let's say you never graduate to that
level. You never want to do that. Does
it matter? Cuz I'll go back to what I
said earlier. With these
um chips, you will be able to perform
effects
that will really wow people. And at the
end of the day, that's what matters. All
right. So, we've talked about the skill
level is beginner, but the effects are
all um professional level.
I would normally at this point talk
about what are the pros and the cons and
the things I wish I knew if I were on
that side of the camera. I think I've
already hit most of my main points. Is
that it's a great entry-level uh at this
uh price point. And if you say these
look like toys and they're too plastic
and they're not play, well, all you have
to do is watch the real-life
performances uh and see that like
they do exactly as they say they do and
that the uh audience can really strongly
react to it. All right, let's get to one
important thing. What do these things
cost? They're $45.
$45 should be north of 500 if they were
coin gaffs. So, uh
but it's just an awesome price point. I
often think like if you are uh
encouraging somebody who's young in
magic uh and you want to buy them a
birthday present or you want to get them
a holiday gift, boy, this will make a
great uh birthday or holiday gift for
them cuz it's a great price point with
magic that they will be able to perform
um and uh get them going uh as well. So,
it's man, I couldn't say enough nice
things about this at this price point.
It's kind of amazing.
All right, that's it. Hey, look, if you
picked up Sucker Punch Revolutions, let
me know. Down below, what are your
thoughts are? Did I uh misrepresent
something in your opinion? Uh was there
something I didn't say that should be
mentioned? Um
if you had the original Sucker Punch,
did you love the original Sucker Punch?
Did you use it at all? I know it sold
really well, but how many of you are
using it? So, um I I is a great next
edition uh of this and Lloyd Barnes who
did the design of these a great job.
Again, Lloyd Barnes and Chef's kiss to
you. Craig Petty, just a nice job on the
tutorial and Murphy's Magic, nice job on
your price point in order to encourage I
think people who are interested in coin
magic
to start with this set and be able to
graduate to more coin magic as they move
on in their magic journey. All right,
that's it. Leave those comments down
below. Hit that like button
and subscribe button. It's really
appreciated and today it is free.
I really do appreciate it very much for
all of you who do so. I really am
grateful.
I'm Fiddlin' Johnny and remember
to keep fiddlin' around with your magic.
I'll see y'all next time. Bye-bye.
>> [music]